A Guide to the Arlington Outdoor Education Association Records, 1947-2017
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
- Photographs
  - Photo Album 1, 1989, 1992-1995, n.d. (Box 16)
  - Photo Album 2 and newspaper clippings, 1987, 1990, 1994, 1996, 2000-2002, n.d. (Box 16)
  - Photo Alubm 3 - Visitors and Students, Construction and Outdoor Lab, 1990-1992, 1994, n.d. (Box 16)
  - Phoebe H. Knipling, Science Supervisor, Arlington VA Public Schools headshot, 1959 (Box 16)
  - Outdoor Lab loose photographs, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Loose Photographs, 1989, 1991, 2000, n.d. (Box 16)
  - Loose Photographs and Negatives, 1985, 1987, 1988, 1990, 1994, 2000 (Box 17)
  - Photo Album 4, February 1994 (Box 17)
- Property
  - Deeds and leases, 1909-1981(not inclusive), 1982, 1985, 2000, 2008 (Box 17)
  - Deeds of easement and land purchase deeds, 1984, 1990, 2000, 2002 (Box 17)
  - Esterbook appraisal, 1978 (Box 17)
  - Mary Rose Striker, 1969 (Box 17)
  - Appraisal of Tahl Corporation property, 1968 (Box 17)
  - Real Estate Reassessment Notices, 2006, 2010 (Box 17)
  - Historic District Designation, 2016 (Box 17)
  - "AOEA Appraisal" [Land Appraisal Reports], 1992-1993 (Box 17)
  - Greene Property Maps and Appraisal, 7907-35-5671, 2013-2014 (Box 17)
  - Gates Property on Biscuit Mountain, 7908-50-7923, Deed, Title Insurance, 2012-2013 (Box 17)
  - "Lawson Property [Research]," 7907-69-9099, 1995, 2000, 2014, n.d. (Box 17)
  - Tyler Estate/Somerville Property, 7907-67-9308, Deed, Sales Contract, Insurance, Correspondence, 2001-2002 (Box 17)
  - Surrounding Property Spreadsheet, Map, and Correspondence, 1988, 2009, n.d. (Box 17)
  - Surveys, Maps, Plats, and Soil Study Map, 1943, 1965, 2009, 2011, n.d. (Box 18)
- Publicity
  - Brochures, 1988, 2014, n.d. (Box 18)
  - Fliers, n.d. (Box 18)
  - Open houses (see also Financial fundraising solicitation files), 1990 (Box 18)
  - Press releases, 1966, 1987 (Box 18)
  - Speeches and promotional material, 1969, 1970, 2001, 2004, 2008, 2013, 2016, n.d. (Box 18)
  - Overhead slide presentation on AOEA, 2005 (Box 18)
  - Outreach, Public Relations, and Communications Plan Proposals and Park After Dark Sponsor Sheet, 2013, 2016 (Box 18)
  - "Info[rmational] Packets", 1967, 1968, 1970, 2005-2006, 2010-2011, n.d. (Box 18)
  - "AOEA [First] Website and [Marketing] Powerpoints," 1999, 2005 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence and Data on AOEA Website and Internet Presence, 2002-2005, n.d. (Box 18)
  - AOEA Mascot, n.d. (Box 18)
- Reading Files
  - 1968 (Box 18)
  - 1969 (Box 18)
  - 1970 (Box 18)
  - 1971 (Box 18)
  - 1972 (Box 18)
  - 1973-1974 (Box 19)
  - 1985 (Box 19)
- Scrapbooks
  - Scrapbook, 1967-1972, 1978-1980 (Box 19)
  - Scrapbook 2, 1983, 1985, 1987, 1989 (Box 19)
  - Scrapbook 3, Outdoor Lab Well and Hemlock Overlook, 1988, n.d. (Box 19)
  - Scrapbook 4, 1990-1993, n.d. (Box 19)
  - Scrapbook 5, 1987, 1989, n.d. (Box 19)
  - Scrapbook in oversize box, 1967, 1978, n.d. (Box 19)
- Slides
  - Fieldtrips, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Fieldtrips I, 1964 (Box 20)
  - Fieldtrips II, 1964, 1966, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Fieldtrips III skyline caverns, 1964, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Fort Detrick and skyline drive, and Smithsonian, 1963 (Box 20)
  - Gemstones, 1974 (Box 20)
  - Great Falls, 1963 (Box 20)
  - Naval Ordinance Lab, Botanical Garden and visiting sci and seminar leaders, 1963 (Box 20)
  - Nike Base and Dulles Beach Erosion and Water Purif. Reservoir, 1963 (Box 20)
  - Outdoor ceremony (unidentified), n.d. (Box 20)
  - Plant Bench and C & O Canal and bus, 1963, 1973 (Box 20)
  - 1959, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Teaching materials center, June 1975 (Box 20)
  - Unidentified, Aug. 1964 (Box 20)
  - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Unidentified, Sept. 1964& Oct. 1977 (Box 20)
  - Slides from Gary to Anita Knipling of Phoebe and others at the Outdoor Lab, 1983 (Box 20)
  - Outdoor Lab, 1993 (Box 20)
- Subject Files
  - Arlington County Fair, 1977, 1979, 1982, n.d. (Box 21)
  - Certificates of appreciation, blank, n.d. (Box 21)
  - Community Resources Study Group, n.d. (Box 21)
  - Food preparation regulations, 1984-1987 (Box 21)
  - Handwritten notes, n.d. (Box 21)
  - Letterhead and stationery, n.d. (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous/Hashawa Environmental Center, 1987, n.d. (Box 21)
  - Proclamations and resolutions, 1987-1997 (Box 21)
  - Service contracts, 1994-1995 (Box 21)
  - Small parks project application form, n.d. (Box 21)
  - Staff, 1978, 1989, 1997 (Box 21)
  - Student representatives, 1990 (Box 21)
  - Telephone, 1995 (Box 21)
  - Virginia Forest Stewardship plan, 1995, n.d. (Box 21)
  - Ecological Community of the Bull Run Mountains, Virginia Report, 2002 (1) (Box 21)
  - Ecological Community of the Bull Run Mountains, Virginia Report, 2002 (2) (Box 21)
  - Does Outdoor Education Really Work Study, 1998 (Box 21)
  - Arlington Chamber of Commerce (Box 22)
  - Planetarium, 1986, 1994 (Box 22)
  - Hemlock Overlook, n.d. (Box 22)
- Summer Camp
  - Attendance, 1995 (Box 22)
  - Budget, 1993-1997 (1) (Box 22)
  - Budget, 1993-1997 (2) (Box 22)
  - Employment, 1994 (Restricted until 2100) (Box 22)
  - Employment, 1995 (Restricted until 2100) (Box 22)
  - Employment, 1996 (Restricted until 2100) (Box 22)
  - Meal menu and kitchen equipment, 1995-1996 (Box 22)
  - Pamphlet, 2017 (Box 22)
- AOEA OVERSIZE BOX
  - Scrapbook
  - Plaques for Dr. Phoebe H. Knipling
- AOEA EPHEMERA BOX
  - Arlington Chamber of Commerce Member Plaque, 2002
  - AOEA Badge
  - AOEA Stickers
  - AOEA Bumper Stickers, 1987
  - AOEA Magnet, 2005
  - 3 AOEA Magnifying glasses
- RESTRICTED BOX
  - From Series 6: Financial
    - Tax Information, 2012 - Open for research
    - Tax Information, 2013 - Open for research
    - Tax Information, 2015 - Closed until 2022
  - From Series 21: Summer Camp
    - Employment, 1994 - Closed until 2100
    - Employment, 1995 - Closed until 2100
    - Employment, 1996 - Closed until 2100